Hey, Kobato!
Yes?
Read this to me!
A firefly's light...
Come on, read it!
Can't you read, Kobato?
I can read perfectly fine!
What shall I do?
Even the obvious things are always so hard
I just want to grin when I'm happy, sing when I'm in love
They say my dreams will come true someday
but when will someday come? I can't wait!
Count one, two, three and spread my arms
Gather the light to myself
Where is it? Tell me what I can do
Even if I'm hurt so much, even if I run so hard
Even if I collapse crying over and over, I still
believe in my amazing future
Night fell, and it got dark.
... Firefly promise.
The man in the moon must be taking a night off.
You can't see it...
Now you can!
You skipped part again!
Sorry...
Ummm...
You're always so dense.
Do your best, Kobato!
Yes!
Oh man, she's screwing up again.
Yomogi Nursery.
I told you, I'm not interested.
We're in session now, so I'm going to have to let you go.
Kobato, you fell again!
You fell again!
Dobato! What are you doing at a time like this!?
Bye-bye, Kobato!
Bye-bye!
Kobato! Kobato!
What is it, Marina?
I hope you get better at reading picture books.
I'll try my best!
You'll be fine. I know you will someday.
Yes!
Um...
I want to practice so I can make everyone happy.
Can I borrow this?
Go ahead.
I want to get better at reading!
Do your best.
Yes!
The firefly had lived alone for a long, long time.
So long he completely forgot he was even a firefly.
Living alone is lonely.
I guess.
It seemed like something good might happen this dark night, but...
Hey, you.
Did you need something?
Yeah. Why don't you knock it off?
I'm telling you, stop reading that.
Um... Why?
He gives me a bad feeling.
What?
It's that old guy from before.
Yeah.
What's up with him?
He seems way different now.
Maybe he's worried about something?
Excuse me!
Don't you have a home?
Why are you asking-
Honestly, I'd stayed in the park until just now too,
but now thanks to Miss Sayaka and Chitose I can sleep on a nice fluffy mattress!
Mattresses are great.
Why don't you stay at my place?
I don't want to rely on someone I don't know!
I'm Hanato Kobato. This is Ioryogi.
Stay away from me.
Excuse me!
Why did he get so angry?
The firefly saw a pretty light far away.
Wondering what it was, he got closer...
I really am dense.
I'll try my best tomorrow!
I overslept again!
You're completely dense.
If you're late, Fujimoto is going to chew you out again.
She's fast!
What's up, babe?
Good morning. How can I help you?
We're here about payment on a loan.
A loan?
They seem pretty dangerous...
Hey, eat up.
I love kids.
C'mon.
Stop it!
What're you doing!?
Oww...
Aren't you gonna apologize for running into me?
The hell are you doing? Lemme go!
Keep your hands off the kids!
Fujimoto!
You-
You'd better respect!
Stop it!
Miss Sayaka!
I thought I told you not to come while we were in session!
Who are you to tell us what to do?
It's your fault for not paying up, right, Teach?
Don't get full of yourself just because the boss is a nice guy!
I'll talk with you after we close. So...
We'll get out of here as soon as you pay us back, so...
I told you, hurry up and pay!
You-
She-
Please, leave...
Kobato?
Please leave!
I don't have time to play with kids!
What's up with that girl?
Police!
Help! There's a stranger!
Come quick!
All right, we'll leave now.
But we'll be back for our money!
Let go of me!
Are you okay, Miss Sayaka?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Toshihiko?
Are you okay?
I was just faking.
I thought if I yelled "police" they'd leave.
Really?
They're really gone.
Amazing!
Toshihiko, you're great!
Nah, no way.
If they come back, I'll chase them off again!
Not bad for you, Dobato.
But how long do you expect me to stay like this?
So they made that phone call yesterday?
They seem to be giving Miss Sayaka a lot of trouble.
Is there anything I can do?
You don't have any money.
But if I pay them back, that will heal Miss Sayaka.
What?
Moron!
It's him.
He's there again?
What's he doing?
This is...
It couldn't be!
Excuse me!
Are you okay?
I'm fine. No problems.
Is there anything I can do?
If you're having any trouble...
I'm not really troubled. I have a home.
I'm here because I want to be.
I see.
The picture book yesterday...
I borrowed it from the nursery.
I've practiced, but I'm still not good at reading it.
I told you not to.
Why?
Everyone likes this story.
So I want to be good at-
Please, don't read it!
Never mind. Forget it.
You hate this picture book that much?
Why are you here, Fujimoto?
I live here.
You're my neighbor?
Isn't that obvious?
Excuse me!
What?
A man at the park told me not to read this picture book.
Oh, you've met Mori?
Mori?
Something to do with Ioryogi?
No, he's the one that wrote that book.
Really?
He's well-known around here.
But why did he tell me not to read it?
Dunno.
But I've heard that's the last book he wrote.
His last book?
On the banks of a pretty stream lived a single firefly.
The firefly had lived alone for a long, long time.
So long he forgot he was even a firefly.
One dark, moonless night,
The firefly saw a pretty light far away.
Wondering what it was, he got closer,
and saw that it was a girl bug.
"You're pretty. What kind of bug are you?", he asked.
"A firefly, just like you." she answered.
And she asked the firefly, "why don't you glow?"
The firefly had lived alone so long that he had forgotten how.
The girl firefly taught the saddened firefly how to glow.
After that, the two lived and glowed happily together on the banks of that stream.
Maybe that old guy forgot how to glow too.
I don't know why, but he's like the firefly in that book.
Maybe I can cheer him up?
Hey, what're you up to?
I'm going to find him!
Hey!
Are you doing anything tonight?
Let's go looking for fireflies!
I'll be waiting at the stream by Mt. Hachiman!
The firefly remembered.
I'm a firefly.
I can glow just like you.
Not bad.
I'm sure you can remember how to glow!
He ain't coming.
You came!
Well, I kinda had to.
The fireflies aren't out yet.
Why did you say that?
"Let's go looking for fireflies. I'll wait for you at the stream by Mt. Hachiman."
Just like Naoko...
Naoko?
She was my lover...
She... Naoko drew that.
She wanted a story about fireflies, so I wrote it and then she drew the pictures after.
Let's go looking for fireflies.
Hey, let's go!
You promised me!
Yes! Understood.
I don't have time.
Come on, I found a great spot.
I told you, I don't have time!
I'll wait for you at the stream by Mt. Hachiman.
I never ended up going.
Hello?
I was so busy with deadlines back then.
So she went alone...
She said it was beautiful, and she had wanted so badly to show me it.
Her art seemed so lonely...
But it was beautiful.
So I rewrote my story to be lonely, yet beautiful.
And once the book was done, I had some time.
You finally have time off!
Yeah. I'll be waiting in the park like always.
Naoko! Hey, Naoko!
Hold on!
Sotaro...
It's me.
Do you want anything? I'll go get it.
Fireflies.
I wanted to see the fireflies with you...
Why didn't I go with her then?
She wanted to go with me so badly...
Why...
I...
I'm leaving.
Wait!
If we just wait a little longer, they'll-
Are you okay?
Sorry!
This is...
This is where Naoko drew...
Here...
The fireflies.
What, you've never seen fireflies?
What's wrong with that?
Let's go see them together!
You've gotta see the real thing!
There aren't any left around here!
I'll show you them!
I promise!
Promise, huh...
The fireflies are beautiful.
Yeah, they're beautiful.
Looks like the old guy remembered how to shine.
He's going to write again.
Look, this proves it.
There's more!
That means-
That you healed the old guy.
I was able to help Mori.
This time you get 100 points, no problem!
Is what I want to say, but...
Deducting for how you treated me at the library...
80 points, Kobato!
Thanks so much!
You'd better get serious from here on!
Yes! I'll try my best!
Wait, I was being way too lenient with 80 points.
Should've gone for 50 or so.
No way! 80 is fine!
Then...
79 points.
That's weird!
People all want to fly
but they're cheated by gravity
everyone can really fly
She must be so unhappy because
she forgot her own shadow somewhere
Then...
If you tell me "thanks", if you say "thanks" and smile
Going back and forth, we'll be happy
You'll be happy, there'll be nothing to worry about
As long as we're together
It's strange, I'm crying even though I'm happy
... Little hide-and-seek.
Next episode